Gabi? Gabi!
What's wrong?
Hey! Get a hold of yourself!
Something wrong? What happened?
I don't know. It's like she's
having some kind of seizure.
Hey! You okay, missy?
Gabi! That's enough!
What's the point of
running away like this?
If we'd stayed in that cell
they would've killed us!
I don't think so.
That guard was worried about you!
You think we can trust those devils?
We can't even trust Zeke anymore!
Or anybody else!
What? Bad dreams?
How I wish all of this had been a dream.
I heard Gabi and Falco calling to me.
Are they safe? Where are they?
We ran all through the night.
So we must've made it pretty far.
Hey. You'd better
take off your armband.
Someone might notice.
I don't care if they do.
Civilians here don't know
what it means anyway.
Yeah, but a soldier would recognize it.
Just take it off to be safe.
Why would a soldier be walking around
out here in the middle of nowhere?
The wrong person will see it eventually.
You don't need it here,
and who knows if we'll
make it back to Marley.
I don't plan to make it back.
I just wanna get some answers from Zeke
before I'm captured and killed.
Why he betrayed us and
why he betrayed Marley.
I just need to find out why he did it.
You can do what you want.
You don't have to follow me.
All right. In that case,
since I can do what I want,
I'll start by trashing your armband.
Give it back!
What's your problem?
That cloth won't help you here
so why do you still wanna wear it?
'Cause it proves I'm
one of the good Eldians!
Without it, I'm no different
than these island devils!
What are you talking about?
You're acting crazy, Gabi!
Just leave me alone then!
Why did you even bother following me?
There's no reason for you to die, too.
What are you doing here?
It's so early in the morning.
Where did the two of you even come from?
I-I don't wanna say.
We hated our home, so much that
we decided to run from it.
So. We can't go back.
I see. You must be hungry.
I live nearby, so follow me and
we can get you some breakfast.
Wait out here for a minute, okay?
Sure.
We should steal horses
and make a break for it.
What are you talking about?
They're gonna send soldiers after us.
We haven't run far enough to be safe.
And besides, I'm not about to eat
alongside a bunch of island devils.
Look, I need you to listen.
All right! Come on in!
'Kay. Thank you!
We'll be right there!
Nevermind, just keep your mouth shut.
I'll do the talking for us both.
Good mornin' to ya.
I hear you're runaways.
Mind if I ask your names?
A southern Marleyan accent?
Nice to meet you!
My name is Ben, sir,
and my kid sister is named Mia.
I can't say why we ran away.
But if you let us stay here
for just a few days,
we'll do anything around here
that needs doing, sir!
We'll work hard! I promise.
So please take us in!
I don't wanna see younguns
like you bowin' your heads.
All are welcome at the Braus Stables.
You can stay as many days as you need.
Table's plenty big,
so sit and get yourselves some breakfast.
You two look exhausted.
Maybe you should lie down
once you've eaten your fill.
Lisa. This girl 'ere...
I'm sorry. I'm sure y'all have
been through quite a lot.
I, uh...
I'm sorry about her.
Thanks. This looks great!
Ow, wow! It's delicious!
Mmm! So good!
Hey. Hurry and eat, Mia.
It seems congratulations are in order,
Premier Zachary.
You bested Marley in battle.
Our leaders back in Hizuru
have nothing but praise
for the courage and cunning displayed
by the nation of Eldia.
I am honored by your words
and by your presence here.
Welcome to the world's
most dangerous island.
Thank you.
That's certainly an apt
description for this place.
And the reason we're here now
is to see that danger for ourselves.
If that's the case,
this must be the observation
craft you mentioned.
It is.
I believe it's the world's
first flying boat,
made possible by your
island's "iceburst stone."
It should enable us
to get a very good look
at the power of the Rumbling.
We've heard rumors that
the Anti-Marleyan Volunteers
have been arrested along
with Eren Jaeger himself.
Can you confirm this?
Please, Hange.
Don't leave us in the dark!
Why did the military suddenly order us
to evacuate Shiganshina?
You were the ones who
put the Reeves Company
in charge of rebuilding it, remember?
Ask the MPs.
Hange! Eren Jaeger's
victory over Marley
has given Eldians like us a future.
A future where our people
have the right to exist.
If that's the case,
then it's only right that
every Eldian in Paradis
should have a voice
in how Jaeger is handled.
As a scout, you said
your job was to explore
and report your findings to us taxpayers.
Are we to assume you
no longer believe this?
The situation has changed.
Now that our walls are open to the world,
we can't trust information
to stay inside them.
I know you're in
a tough spot here. I get it.
So just look me in the eye
and tell me I can trust you.
I can promise you that everything we do,
we do for the sake of the people.
So it was the four of you
who leaked these rumors about Eren?
Three recruits:
Holger, Wim, and Louise.
And one veteran: Floch.
Care to tell me why you did it?
Because Eren never should've
been imprisoned.
He's done nothing wrong
and should be freed at once.
He challenged a powerful, imposing enemy,
and grasped victory.
We now have the Rumbling.
A power which secures our right to live.
Eren Jaeger is no criminal.
He's a war hero.
And he just saved
the life of every person
in the New Eldian Empire.
The Nation of Eldia is
in greater danger than ever.
We don't know if the Rumbling
can protect us yet or not.
Nobody knows how it works,
it's still just a myth at this point.
Only because you're
keeping Eren locked in a cage.
At the very least,
I hope you'll agree that
we can't afford to waste time right now.
We need to be decisive.
To make use of our victory.
It will be Eren Jaeger
who leads this nation.
Please see reason and
release him at once.
Yeah. You might just
be right about that.
From a certain viewpoint.
I've already made the decision
to see Zeke Jaeger's plan
through to the end.
I'm responsible for making that choice.
Which is why I can't
tolerate insubordination.
You will all be tried for the crime of
leaking confidential intelligence.
Detain them in the meantime.
If this is the price of serving humanity
within the walls, then so be it.
There's an order to these things.
Perhaps it's a law of human nature.
When one's time is over,
another must take on the role
that they used to play.
Best of luck, Hange.
I'm pooped.
No. There's more
I need to investigate.
This may sound strange,
but have you ever been
in this cell, Mikasa?
Uh... No, I haven't.
Well, that's too bad.
I had kind of hoped.
Either way, I have no regrets
about leaking that intel.
The Scout regiment's goal is victory.
And if military law becomes
an obstacle to that goal,
there's nothing to do
but bend the rules, right?
Don't talk like that, Louise.
You'll just extend your sentence.
About four years have passed
since you saved me from a Titan,
and nothing has changed for me.
I watched you bring one of them down
with nothing but human strength.
And realized that you can't
protect others without power.
That it's okay to fight
against senseless violence.
It's necessary.
Ever since that day,
I've hoped I'd get a chance
to get closer to you.
That's why I...
Tell me, Mikasa.
Why did you join the Scout Regiment?
If it was for Jaeger,
you should set him fr...
I only have one thing to say to you.
Keep your mouth shut, Louise.
You're safe now.
Mikasa.
Ten months ago,
during the celebration of the
opening of the Trost Railway.
The guard assigned to watch over you
was changed at the last minute.
Changed to Floch Forster.
Whilst everyone else was
busy enjoying the festivities,
Forster accompanied you to your lodgings.
He's since been charged with
divulging military secrets.
I thought to check and
it turns out that your lodgings
were just a few dozen
kilometers from Eren Jaeger's.
It also turns out to be around then
that we started to see Eren
take more unauthorized actions.
On the bright side,
this means I have an excuse to
speak with a beautiful woman.
Gabi. Gabi!
Gabi!
Why is this happening to me?
I know. This is
the devil's doing!
No. I think the horse
was working alone.
You know, there
probably isn't a horse here
that would let you ride on it.
I never learned to ride anyway,
so it doesn't matter.
We won't learn anything if we
stay out here in the sticks.
Yeah, but we're better off laying low
than roaming around, for now at least.
What's that supposed to mean?
I think we can just hang
tight and wait for help.
It's only a matter of time before
Marley and the rest of the world attack.
When they do, I bet that
Reiner and my brother
will come and rescue us.
Aren't you pissed at Zeke?
All this time, we've had
a traitor right next to us!
Uh... There's nothing we can do about it.
Where the hell didja get
the name "Mia" from?
And why'd you call me your "kid" sister?
Does it really matter?
Hey, you two.
Ready for a lunch break?
Both of you are quick learners.
You're hard-working, too.
You think? Thanks for saying so.
Hey, Kaya, I wanted to ask you.
Is there a reason why everyone
who works at this place
is so young?
Yeah. For the most part,
we're all orphans.
Oh. I see.
The queen's policies
provide a lot of support
to children with nowhere to go.
Most of the kids who
live here at the stables
lost our parents four years ago.
You haven't acknowledged
your guilt yet, have you?
You people can cover it up
and try to forget,
but you've committed horrific atrocities
against the entire world.
There's only one way for an Eldian
to start down the path towards atonement.
And that's to recognize that
you are tainted with sin.
Are you saying this
'cause it has to do with
why we lost our parents?
Of course it does.
Even if you act like
a saint your whole life,
you'll never escape from
the shadow of Eldia's sins.
[KAYA] I guess that's what they
teach you back in Marley?
[FLACO]Why you say something like this when someone who's helping us?
These are indisputable truths!
[GABI] She needs to be told.
[FLACO] Please don't do this.
Whoa, wait a minute,
what did you just say?
You're on the run because
you're from Marley, right?
How did you know?
Do you really have to ask?
You were yelling about going back.
Wait. So then,
you knew from the start?
Aww man.
From the moment we first met?
This is seriously embarrassing.
Why didn't you say something about it?
Jeez. You're so sneaky.
What do you think you're doing?
Take a guess!
She just showed her true colors!
I knew something was up with her!
There's no way an island devil
would actually be that nice!
Stop! Don't be stupid!
Hey!
What're you two fighting about?
This is bad.
Mia thinks I'm stealing her brother.
I think she's jealous or something!
It looks like
Kaya's actually making friends.
I guess she's cheered up some.
Good grief.
Well, don't horse around with
that pitchfork, it's sharp!
Right. Sorry!
Why?
This village used to be my home.
Four years ago, a Titan showed up here.
It was only a small one,
but everyone still ran when they saw it.
Everyone except for my mother,
who couldn't run.
There was nothing I
could do, so I just sat.
Right at this spot.
I sat still and listened to the sound
of that Titan eating my mother.
She was alive the entire
time it was happening,
but after a while,
she went mostly silent.
Think she lost her voice
from all the screaming.
We've been told that
outside of the walls,
the majority of people
think we're a race of devils.
But I don't understand
how people we've never met
can hate us so much.
So please. Help me. Explain it.
What have we ever done to them?
What did my mom do
to make these people hate her?
For thousands
of years, your kind brutalized
and slaughtered people
all over the world!
Thousands of years?
How could you have
let yourselves forget this?
Eldians used the Power of
the Titans to crush the world
beneath their heels for
millennia, understand?
They wiped out other people's cultures,
forced those people
to bear their children,
and took more innocent lives
than you could possibly imagine!
So stop playing like you're the victim!
But my mother spent her
whole life here on this island.
She couldn't have had
anything to do with all that.
Listen to me!
A century ago,
your ancestors ruled the world
by doing awful, unforgivable things!
A century ago? Okay, but what
about the people here now?
What unforgivable things have we done?
You attacked Marley the other day.
Your soldiers devastated my home.
But that was recent,
and my mom was killed
four whole years ago.
So that's not her fault.
The point is your ancestors slaughtered
countless people all over the world!
But my mother didn't kill anybody!
Tell me! Why'd she have to die?
She never hurt a soul, so why?
It must've been for something, right?
It doesn't make sense otherwise!
Is the world we live in
just that horrible
or was there a reason?
Spit it out! Why was
my mom eaten alive?!
Tell me! Tell me why!
Reconnaissance-in-force.
The incursion four years ago was part of
a recon mission to
gauge Paradis' strength
and prepare for a larger attack.
You and your mother just
happened to get caught up in it.
Your mom was innocent,
she didn't deserve that.
I'm sorry.
You're leaking secrets to the enemy now?
Why the hell did you apologize?
Thank you for telling me, Ben.
I'm glad to know.
But um, you don't have to
apologize for Marley.
I mean you just happened
to be born there.
Hey, Kaya.
If you were trapped in here with a Titan,
how did you manage to escape?
A girl not much older than I am
saw what was happening,
grabbed an axe from our yard,
and came in swinging.
She saved me.
No way! For real?
Yeah. She put herself
between me and the Titan,
and held it off so I could escape.
If she was still alive,
she would never abandon two
lost kids with nowhere to run.
She'd help you, just like she helped me.
Mr. Braus was invited
to go to a restaurant
where a Marleyan works.
If the two of you join us,
then maybe that Marleyan
can help you to find a way back home.
Why do this?
It's simple. I wanna be
the kind of person she was.
We investigated the Beast Titan's remains
and managed to locate a number of
Zeke Jaeger's severed body parts.
But no. Not enough.
Just his arms and legs.
This effectively confirms our theory:
Zeke conspired with the
enemy to stage his death
in order to hide the fact that
he has defected to their side.
We now believe that Zeke is the traitor
we have long suspected
to be among our ranks.
This here is the Anti-Personnel
ODM gear used to attack us.
It utilizes Marleyan tech.
Then there's the matter of
how they escaped on a stolen airship.
Only a veteran pilot could've
executed such advanced maneuvers.
Zeke must've snuck his co-conspirators
onto the first Survey Fleet
we sent to Paradis.
A handpicked cell of
Eldian Restorationists.
Shit. To think
we fought side-by-side
with a traitor this whole time.
Of course, we're not
about to let it end here.
As part of a global alliance,
we'll launch a scorched-earth campaign
against Paradis within six months.
Wait. We're waiting that long?
We're not gonna try to save
Falco and Gabi for six months?
They're the most talented
Warrior candidates we have, sir.
If we lost them before
they even got to inherit,
it would be a major blow to Marley.
Training new candidates
isn't just expensive.
It also takes a number
of years to do right.
That's true, but if Marley attempts
to attack Paradis without backup,
we'll only be driven back
like we were before.
We must wait for the
allied forces to gather.
That's exactly what Zeke hopes we'll do.
He's betting that Marley won't
dare launch a counterattack
right after taking such a heavy blow.
If we give him half a year to prepare,
he'll fight back
in ways we can't predict.
We can't afford to
wait for the global alliance!
We have no choice.
We need to attack them at once.
How should one decide who to hate?
How should one decide what to blame?
By now, you would think that one would be
used to the shifting of truth.
Next episode: "Guides."